tonic.com 2011-06-30

# 

At Tonic, your privacy and security are critical to us. We guard it with our lives. See below for details.

**Tonic Privacy Policy & Statement of Security**

Last updated: 2/28/2011

This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) applies to information that we obtain in connection with your use of the Tonic Generation Inc. (“Tonic”) website [www.tonic.com](http://www.tonic.com/) and other related owned and operated websites (the "Sites"). More specifically, the Policy is designed to tell you how we collect and use personal information (as defined below) so you can make an informed decision about using our Sites. Please read this statement before using our Sites or submitting any personal information to us. By using our Sites, you represent that you are 13 years old or older and you consent to the information collection and use practices described herein. **We reserve the right to change the provisions of this privacy policy at any time by posting a revised privacy policy on the Sites and indicating on the privacy policy the date it was last updated. Your use of the Sites following the posting of such changes or revised statement shall constitute your acceptance of any such changes.** We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you visit our Sites to determine if any changes have been made and to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.

**Information We May Collect**

As used herein, the term "personal information" generally means information that specifically identifies an individual (such as user's name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card or other account number) or that is associated with an identifiable person (such as demographic information or information about a person's activities when such information is linked to personally identifying information). However, personal information does not cover any publicly available information and public records, and websites that are available to the public. Personal information also does not include "aggregate" information, which is data we collect about the use of the Sites or categories of its users, from which any personal information has been removed. For example, information that forty-seven percent of a one of the Sites registered users identify themselves as female is aggregate information. We collect aggregate data for a number of purposes, including helping us understand trends and user needs so that we can better consider new publications, products and services, and tailor existing publications, products and services to user desires. This policy in no way limits or restricts our collection of aggregate information.

**Information We May Collect**

You can browse the Sites without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. However, once you give us any of your personal information, you are no longer anonymous to us. If you choose to provide us with personal information, you consent to our use of such information as provided for in this Policy, including, but not limited to the transfer and storage of that information to our servers located in the United States. You may provide personal information to Tonic in a number of ways including: (1) by creating an account; (2) signing up for The Daily Tonic or other Tonic newsletter; (3) by logging in with Facebook Connect; (4) by purchasing our postal junk mail reduction service, Precycle or other Tonic products; or (5) by sharing personal information when you post comments on our posts or stories. We may collect and store the following personal information:

  * email address, physical contact information, and financial information, such as credit card numbers;
  * computer sign-on data, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the site, and ad data;
  * other information that is not personally identifiable, including IP address and standard web log information, operating system and browser and the domain name of your internet provider.

Where we have designed our Sites to let you send personal data to Tonic, your transmission will be protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL). SSL is a technology that encrypts your information during transmission and will be apparent by a lock image on your browser or by a URL starting with “https.”

The mailing address information you provide us will only be used to provide the products or services you request. Credit card information will be used only to process payments for your orders and will not be stored on Tonic’s servers. We do not retain credit card information.

**Use**

Our primary purposes in collecting personal information are to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized online experience. You agree that we may use your personal information to:

  * provide the products, services, and customer support you request;
  * process payments, collect fees, resolve disputes, and troubleshoot problems;
  * manage your activities on the site including voting for causes, suggesting causes, sharing content, and creating and managing events;
  * prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our Terms of Use;
  * customize, measure, and improve our services and our website's content and layout; and
  * communicate with you regarding Tonic products and services and issues of interest to the Tonic customer community (unless you opt out of these communications, which we will enable you to do).

To maintain that our media Sites remain free of charge and do not require registration, we may display advertising on various pages within any of our Sites. While ads may be placed by third-party advertisers not affiliated with Tonic, at no time does any party other than the third-party advertisers have access to your personally identifiable information and you will never be contacted by any party other than Tonic. However, in special campaigns with third-party partners, as we deem appropriate, (e.g. Angiogenesis Foundation), we may share your personally identifiable information after we allow you to opt-in or opt-out.

**Our Disclosure of Your Information**

It is Tonic's policy not to trade, sell, lease or distribute any of your personal information, except as needed to provide you with the products and services you elect to receive from us or our business partners or as otherwise provided in this Policy. We also may disclose personal information when we are required to or we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant or court order); to enforce or apply this Policy or our other policies or agreements; to initiate, render, bill, and collect for amounts owed to us; to protect our or our customers' rights, property or safety; to protect our customers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of our Sites; or if we believe that an emergency involving the danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of personal information. In addition, information about our customers, including personal information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personally identifiable information could be transferred to third parties as one of the business assets of Tonic.

**Cookies**

We use "cookies" (small files placed on your hard drive to recognize users who have previously visited a Site and retain certain information such as preferences and history) on certain pages of our Sites to help analyze our web page flow, customize our services, and measure promotional effectiveness. A few important things you should know about cookies are that:

  * We offer certain features that are only available through the use of cookies.
  * We use cookies to help identify you and maintain your signed-in status.
  * Most cookies are "session cookies", meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session.
  * If we combine cookies with or link them to any of the personally identifying information, we would treat this information as personal information.
  * You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of the site including access to certain features or services.

**Accessing, Reviewing and Changing Your Personal Information**

You can see, review and change most of your personal information by logging into your account on the Sites. You must promptly update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. To opt out of receiving promotional communications or newsletters from Tonic, please follow the unsubscribe instructions included with the communication, check the opt-out box on your logged-in account page or contact us at [customerservice@tonic.com](mailto:customerservice@tonic.com?subject=Custom%20Service) for help. Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable law. We do retain personal information from closed accounts in order to comply with law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law.

**Security**

Tonic endeavors to secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure by putting into place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect through the Sites. For example, when we collect credit card information, we use a secure server with Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption software and store such credit card information using encryption methods designed to prevent unauthorized access. Additionally, your account information is accessible online only through the use of a password. Please be aware, however, that despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. To protect the confidentiality of your personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of the Sites by any person using your password. Please advise us immediately by email us at [customerservice@tonic.com](mailto:customerservice@tonic.com?subject=Custom%20Service) if you believe your password has been misused. You should also note that email is not secure, and you should not send any confidential or sensitive information to us via an unsecured email.

Your information is stored on our servers located in the United States. We treat data as an asset and endeavor, with industry standard tools (encryption, passwords, physical security, etc.), to protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure. To protect the confidentiality of your personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of the Sites by any person using your password. Please advise us immediately by email us at [customerservice@tonic.com](mailto:customerservice@tonic.com?subject=Custom%20Service) if you believe your password has been misused. You should also note that email is not secure, and you should not send any confidential or sensitive information to us via an unsecured email.

All personal and credit card information is protected by the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol with a minimum 128 bit encryption. SSL creates a secure communication channel by encrypting all communication between the user and server. As long as you see the padlock in your browser window you are secure.

While we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. Also, please be aware that despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from our Sites.

All personal and credit card information is protected by the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol with a minimum 128-bit encryption. SSL creates a secure communication channel by encrypting all communication between the user and server. As long as you see the padlock in your browser window you are secure.

Payments are processed through Authorize.net, a payment network that is trusted by more than 220,000 merchants nationwide. Additionally, all of your sensitive information is encrypted on our systems. It is our policy to take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data is securely maintained with access limited to only those who need such access to serve you.

**Links to Other Sites**

Our Sites may contain links to other websites (some of which may be in the form of links in articles and Tonic Profiles, blogs or other interactive forums, banner ads, partner products and other advertisements). Please be aware that although we may participate in or utilize such other sites, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites, and our linking to these websites does not indicate any endorsement of these websites or any affiliation with their providers. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data, and/or solicit personal information from you. Similarly, if you entered our Sites through another website, we are also not responsible for the privacy practices of that site, and you should review the privacy policy of the originating site before providing any personal information to that site. You must check the privacy statements of these other websites to understand their policies for collecting and using such information.

**Our Policy Towards Children**

This site is not directed towards children. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personal information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [privacy@tonic.com](mailto:privacy@tonic.com?subject=Privacy%20inquiry), and we will delete such information from our files.

**Business Transfers**

Tonic may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your personal information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy. We will use our reasonable efforts to require our successor to continue to protect your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Privacy Errors**

We strive to update and improve our website and associated services on an ongoing basis. Because certain elements of our Sites or services may be in testing phase at any particular time, we may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. We therefore welcome feedback on any privacy concerns you may have, and on how to improve our services generally. We do not guarantee error-free performance under this Privacy Policy. We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this Privacy Policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply. We will not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is governed by the laws of the United States.

**Questions**

If you have any questions regarding this policy, please write us at [privacy@tonic.com](mailto:privacy@tonic.com?subject=Privacy%20inquiry).
